I noticed a pair of shoes I did not recognize when I got home from school.
我放学回家后看见一双没看过的鞋子
I instantly realized they were Senior Yuri's shoes.
我立刻意识到那是由梨学姐的鞋子
But my mind was blank at that moment.
但当时我脑中一片空白
I dashed to my brother's room
我不假思索地奔向我哥的房间
and opened his door without knocking.
没敲门就推开了房门
And then…
结果...
And then…?
结果...？
Then I saw Se-Senior Yuri being pinned down by my brother.
我就看见 由梨学姐被压在我哥身体下方...
They were kissing…!
他们在接吻...
(A Cup of Coffee With a Milk to Coffee Ratio of 8:2) In other words,
(来杯咖啡 牛奶咖啡比例8:2 放一小匙砂糖 再加焦糖粉) 也就是说
(Add a Teaspoon of White Sugar and Caramel Powder) Ichinose is here
(来杯咖啡 牛奶咖啡比例8:2 放一小匙砂糖 再加焦糖粉) 一之濑同学是因为
because she is having difficulty confronting her brother.
难以面对她哥哥
She feels she can't go on like this, and she needs to do something,
觉得不能再这样下去 想做点改变
so she comes to work in this second-hand bookstore.
所以她才来这家二手书店打工
Even though she wishes to continue relying on her beloved brother,
尽管她很想继续依赖自己最爱的哥哥
she is unable to do so because he has a girlfriend.
但哥哥交了女友后就无法这么做
So she decided to stop relying on her brother.
她只好决定不再依赖哥哥
And, in order to foster this spirit of independence,
然后她为了培养自立的精神
she cannot easily give up her job.
所以她不能轻易放弃这份打工
That's how it is.
就是这么一回事吧
I got it.
我明白了
So Ichinose, you've made up your mind.
看来一之濑同学你已下定了决心
You have to work hard then.
那就好好加油吧
Ichinose's work has been
从那之后 一之濑同学工作时
consistently outstanding since then.
她真的表现得很出色
Maybe she took yesterday's incident as a declaration of her determination.
也许昨天的事情对她来说 算是宣示了她的决心吧
She's full of energy now.
现在她的非常积极
Good!
好
I always hear that working allows one to bury the hurt inside.
常听到有人说 可以靠工作来填补受伤心灵的空洞
Though I've only seen it in TV shows or comics.
虽然我也只在电视剧或漫画里看到过
Leave it to me.
交给我吧
Thanks.
谢啦
Ichinose's affairs have always felt like my own.
总觉得一之濑同学的事 好像变成我自己的事一样
So the remaining issue is, of course, hosting customers.
剩下的难题就是接待客人了吗
Hosting customers?
接待客人
Did you hear that?
被你听到了啊
Don't worry, I can handle tough customers.
你放心 难对付的客人就交给我
Just watch me do it first.
你就先看我怎么做吧
We have a customer.
有客人
Welcome.
欢迎光...
Welcome, Miss Sasaki.
笹木小姐欢迎光临
Ichinose, this is Miss Sasaki.
一之濑同学 这位是笹木小姐
You may not believe it, but she's a junior high school student.
虽然有点难以置信 但她是个初中生
Junior high school student…?
初中生...？
Miss Sasaki, this is Ichinose.
笹木小姐 这是一之濑同学
She's new here and is in the same grade as me.
她是新进员工 跟我同年级
You're in the same grade as you, Mr. Sajo?
你跟佐城先生同年级吗
Nice to meet you, Senior Ichinose.
一之濑学姐 请多指教
Uh, nice to meet you.
呃...请多指教 学妹
It's a rare occasion for Miss Sasaki to come here.
笹木小姐难得又来店里
Even though I'd like to talk to her for a long time,
虽然我也想跟她好好聊个天
I'm only thinking about Ichinose at the moment.
但老实说我现在 光是一之濑同学的事就够忙的了
No, wait.
不 等等
Miss Sasaki, you and Ichinose may get along.
笹木小姐 你跟一之濑同学可能很聊得来哦
Because Ichinose also likes reading.
因为她也很喜欢阅读
Really?
真的吗
I don't have any friends who enjoy reading, so I'm glad to have met you.
我身边没什么人喜欢阅读 所以真是开心
Please be my good friend.
请你跟我当好朋友吧
I do have a habit of reading, but…
我是有在阅读啦...但...
Miss Sasaki seems very happy.
笹木小姐看起来很开心
Perhaps the awkwardness will fade away now.
或许气氛就不会这么尴尬了吧
B-But I'm working now…
但...现在我在上班
Sorry.
对不起
No, it's fine.
不 没关系
You can swap with me when the customer arrives.
等客人来了你再继续工作就好了
May I ask what kind of books do you usually read, Senior Ichinose?
一之濑学姐你平常都看什么书呢
I don't have any preferences.
我没有特别偏好
I'll read it as long as the title and cover appeal to me.
只要觉得书名跟封面吸引我...
That's amazing, you really like "books" themselves.
好厉害 你是真的喜欢书籍耶
That's so cool.
好帅气
Who's your favorite author? What's your favorite genre?
那你喜欢的作家是谁 还有你喜欢哪种题材呢
-Even though you just said you don't have any preferences. -I'll go sort out the books.
-虽然你刚才说没特别偏好 -我去整理一下书本咯
What kinds of titles and covers, for example, would pique your interest?
例如什么样的书名跟封面会吸引你呢
How long does it take you to finish a book?
你大概都多久看完一本书呢
It depends on the book.
那要看是什么书
Understand. Sometimes you want to finish slowly and leave it for tomorrow.
我懂 有时候会舍不得看完 故意留到隔天再看
In some cases, you finish a story in one sitting because you're curious.
有时候又会想知道后续发展 而一口气看完
Do you have any recommendations?
你有什么推荐的书吗
Don't books recommended by people
喜欢阅读的人所推荐的书
who enjoy reading feel a little more special?
你不觉得会有种特别的感觉吗
Indeed.
这倒是没错...
Great.
太好了
-How about this one? -Despite her reserved demeanor, she can now communicate.
-那...这本如何 -虽然她偏被动 但还是有好好应答
I've read this before and it's interesting.
这本我之前看过 觉得很有意思
So I'm recommending it to you.
所以我很推荐
-Wow, that's great! -But no customers are coming. If this continues,
-哇 太棒了 -但客人再不上门的话...
-Thank you for your recommendation, -Ichinose can't practice on hosting customers.
-谢谢你 -一之濑同学就无法练习接待客人了
Okay, let's pretend to be customers. Scenario simulation begins.
好 我们来角色扮演一下 模拟接待客人
Go for it, Senior Ichinose.
一之濑学姐加油
Why aren't there any magazines here?
你们这里没有杂志吗
There… aren't any.
没...没有
Why aren't there any?
为什么没有啊
W-Why…?
为...什么...
I-I'll ask the boss.
我...去问一下老板
Good, this kind of response is not bad.
好 这种应对方式也可以
Let me teach you another way to respond…
我来教你另一种应对方法...
Where is she? She didn't really go to the shop owner, did she?
人呢？她不会真的去找老板了吧
Good, just do it like that.
很好 继续保持
I'm sorry.
对不起...
It's okay, the boss is also happy.
没关系啦 老板心情也不错
Is this what part-time work is…?
打工就是这么一回事吗
Now it's Miss Sasaki's turn to play the customer.
接下来轮到笹木小姐
Can you play a troublesome customer?
你可以扮演一下找碴的客人吗
Okay! Leave it to me.
好的 包在我身上
This is also a step towards adulthood! It's social learning.
这也是长大成人的过程 我要学习适应社会
That's nice.
好羡慕哦
Don't worry, everyone has their own strengths!
别在意 大家各有各的好
I-I'm going to start.
那...我要开始咯
Hey, you bastard.
喂喂喂 你这家伙
Thanks.
谢啦
This troublesome customer has a strong personality.
这位找碴的客人真是个性十足啊
Thank you for your patronage.
多谢惠顾
I'll come again.
我还会再来的
Senior Ichinose, by the way,
对了 一之濑学姐
I'll finish the book you recommended before my next visit.
我会看完你推荐的书之后再来的
Huh? There's no need…
呃...倒也不必...
She resembles a lily of the valley swaying in the breeze.
她就像一朵随风摇曳的铃兰...
Miss Sasaki was our only customer today.
今天的客人就只有笹木小姐耶
-There will be days like this. -Yes.
-有时候就是会这样 -好的
She's just like that, please take care of her.
她人就是这样 麻烦你多担待了
That's great. You'll have someone to chat with after I quit.
幸好我离职之后也有人能陪你聊天了
You're quitting?
你要离职吗
Don't you know? We began hiring new staff because I am resigning.
你不知道吗 就是因为这样所以才招新人的啊
As you can see,
如你所见
this shop doesn't need so many staffs.
这间店并不需要这么多员工
Although I'm not sure if you'll be able
虽然不知道你的目的能不能达成
to achieve your goal, let me be your senior until then.
在那之前就让我当你的前辈吧
Thank you.
谢谢你
I'll go sort out the bookshelf.
我去整理书柜
Is it almost time to finish?
下班时间也快到了
After the summer vacation,
等暑假结束
I'll probably become distant from Ichinose again.
我跟一之濑同学想必又会疏远了吧
But why would she talk to me about her family situation?
不过她为什么会跟我聊家里的事啊
HOW'S YOUR JUNIOR AT WORK?
(打工的后辈还好吗)
I ASKED HER, SHE SEEMS TO WANT TO BE INDEPENDENT.
(她跟我说她想自立更生)
IS HER SITUATION THAT DIFFICULT?
(她生活这么辛苦吗)
OTHERWISE, PEOPLE USUALLY DON'T THINK ABOUT BEING INDEPENDENT.
(不然一般 不会想要自立更生吧)
YES
(是啊)
Huh? You're here?
什么嘛 原来你在啊
A cup of coffee with a milk to coffee ratio of 8:2.
来杯咖啡 牛奶咖啡比例8:2
Add a teaspoon of white sugar and caramel powder.
放一小匙砂糖 再加焦糖粉
Can you wait a minute for me?
你可以等我一分钟吗
It takes that long?
要等这么久吗
I'll do it right now.
我马上准备
YOU'LL HAVE TO TELL US EVERYTHING ONCE SCHOOL STARTS
(等开学你再跟我们详细说)
Yes.
遵...命...
I got it.
我懂了
Ichinose confided in me because she didn't have anyone else to confide in.
一之濑同学会跟我说那么多 是因为她没有其他人可以倾诉
At school, she's always alone.
在学校里她总是孤零零一个人
At home, it's the same.
在家也是
I wouldn't be hearing about her family situation
要是她有个女性好友的话
if she had even one female friend.
她就不会跟我说她家里的事了吧
-Not done yet? -It's done. Coming right up.
-还没好吗 -好了 马上来
Don't keep the customer waiting.
别让客人久候好吗
Sorry for the wait.
让您久等了
Geez.
真是的
Is there something on your mind?
你是有什么心事吗
No, why?
没有啊
You're not drinking it anymore?
你这样就不喝了吗
It's so bad!
好难喝
You don't have to carry as much as I do,
你不用像我一次搬这么多
just what you can handle.
慢慢来就好
Thank you.
谢谢你
-Here you go. -Okay.
-拿去 -啊...好
She looks like a hardworking elementary school student.
她怎么看都像是个很努力的小学生
Welcome.
欢迎光临
Not bad.
你刚这样很不错耶
EGG MOOD
(鸡蛋的心情)
OMELETTE RICE OF THE DAY
(每日一道蛋包饭)
Brother.
哥哥...
Hello.
你好
Yuri said she will make omelette rice for me.
小由梨说她要煮蛋包饭给我吃
Mina, would you like to join us?
深那学妺你要一起吃吗
I'm really looking forward to your cooking.
我好期待小由梨你的手艺哦
Leave it to me, this is my specialty.
交给我吧 这可是我的拿手好菜
I can't wait.
真期待
My rice has the shape of a heart.
我的蛋包饭上有爱心耶
Not bad.
煮得不错
I wonder how it tastes.
不知道味道如何
Mina?
深那？
E-Excuse me…
请问...
BINAN BOOKSTORE How do I do this?
(滨南书店) 这个该怎么弄
This? First do this, then this.
这个要像这样...
Let me try.
我来试试看
First this.
先这样
Then this.
再这样
Perfect.
完美
Speaking of which, Ichinose, you're extremely gentle with the books.
一之濑同学你对书本超级温柔的耶
Unlike me when I first started.
不像我刚开始的时候
The boss chastised me and advised me to be more gentle with the books.
被老板嘱咐要对商品再温柔一点
I think this is a great thing about you.
你很厉害耶
Really?
是吗
Yes, I admire it.
嗯 我很佩服
W-What's wrong?
怎...怎么了吗
I think you shouldn't cover your face with your bangs.
我觉得你平常就不该用浏海 遮住自己的脸
Oh no, what a pick-up line.
糟糕 我这是什么撩妹发言
Ah! Don't misunderstand!
啊 你别误会
I-Is that so?
是...这样吗
S-So cute.
好可爱啊
Um…
那个啊
Sorry, what's wrong?
抱歉 怎么了吗
No, nothing.
没什么啦
Am I about to retire too?
我也快退役了
But, in this way, I can begin the new semester with no worries.
不过这样 我就能毫无顾虑地迎接新学期了
Excuse me, may I ask…
不好意思 请问一下
What's the matter?
怎么了吗
Senior Kuma. Does that mean…
熊学长 也就是说...
Mina.
深那
(Dreaming Boy is a Realist, The)
《满怀美梦的少年是现实主义者》
BINAN BOOKSTORE, USED BOOK RECYCLING
(滨南书店 旧书回收)
So you're here, I had a hard time finding you.
原来你在这里 我找你找得好辛苦
Because you told Mom not to tell me where you were.
因为你叫妈妈不要告诉我你在哪
By the way, are you about to get off work?
你正好要下班了吧
-Occasionally eating out together… -No.
-我们偶尔一起在外面吃... -我不要...
Mina. Sorry, who are you?
深那...不好意思 请问你是？
My name is Sajo.
我叫佐城
I'm your sister's senior at work,
我跟你妹妹在这里是前辈后辈的关系
but we're classmates at school.
但我们在学校是同学
I assure you that I'm not in that kind of relationship with your sister.
我跟你妹妹没什么特别的关系...
Sorry, Sajo, could you step aside please?
抱歉佐城同学 你可以先退下吗
Oh, okay.
啊 好的
Ichinose?
一之濑同学？
She keeps looking at me.
她一直盯着我
No, wait, Sajo Wataru.
等等 佐城涉
-It's my fault. -Why is she hiding behind me?
-是哥哥我不好 -她为什么要躲在我身后
-I'm sorry. I didn't consider your feelings. -I don't know who to speak for.
-是我没考虑到你的心情 抱歉 -我到底该帮谁话说啊
How about we go somewhere cooler first?
那个... 你们要不要去凉快一点的地方？
It's not the time to worry about that.
我现在顾不了那么...
Is it okay to leave your sister out in this scorching sun?
这样让你妹妹曝晒在烈日下 你真的无所谓吗
Okay then.
好吧
There's a place nearby where we can sit down and talk.
这附近有个可以坐下聊聊的地方
Senior, please use this.
学长 这个给你用
Thank you.
谢谢你
It's indeed hot today.
天气太热了
Sorry, Sajo.
抱歉啊佐城同学
I was acting rashly right now.
刚才是我太冲动了
It's okay, senior.
没关系 学长你不用在意
Mina, it's my fault.
深那 是我不好
Excuse me, Ichinose.
请问一之濑...
Do you know why your sister started working?
学长你知道你妹妹为什么想打工吗
I never asked her directly,
我没有直接问过她
so I only know a rough idea.
所以只知道个大概
Haven't you guys talked since then?
难道在那之后你们都没讲过话吗
So that's how it is.
原来是这样…
Mina, are you willing to listen to me?
深那 你可以听我说吗
What do you want to say, brother?
哥哥你要说什么
It was my fault for not paying attention to you
我不该在跟小由梨交往后
after I started dating Yuri.
就把你晾在一旁 都是我的错
Let's be together like we used to, reading books and sleeping together.
我们就回到以前那么亲密 一起看书一起睡觉好吗
Brother, you belong to Senior Yuri now.
哥哥你已经属于由梨学姐了
Yuri won't mind these things.
小由梨不会在意这种事
But… it's not fair to Senior Yuri.
可是我会对由梨学姐很过意不去
You don't have to worry.
你不用在意这些
Yuri is very understanding.
小由梨她很善解人意
Can you understand me, Mina?
深那 你能体谅我吗...
Sorry to keep you waiting, Ichinose!
久等了一之濑同学
Hey, you've got to be kidding me.
不会吧...
Yuri, you're here.
小由梨你来了啊
Because I think this is not only a problem between Ichinose and Mina.
毕竟我觉得这不只是 你跟深那学妹之间的问题
May I ask who you are?
这位是？
My name is Sajo.
我叫佐城
I work part-time with Ichinose, and we go to the same school.
我跟一之濑同学一起打工 在学校也是同学
My name is Hanaoka Yuri. Nice to meet you.
我叫花冈由梨 请多指教
It's been a long time, Mina.
深那学妹 我们好久不见了
Yes.
啊 嗯...
I heard you suddenly started working.
听说你突然开始打工
Your brother and I were wondering what happened.
我跟你哥哥就想说是怎么回事
But it seems to be my fault.
但似乎跟我有关...
I'm sorry.
对不起
I intruded into your life without asking.
是我擅自闯入了你的生活
Part-time work must be difficult for you, Mina, given your personality.
以深那学妹的个性 对你来说打工一定很辛苦吧
I think it's still too early for you.
我觉得对你来说还太早了
It's not too early!
才不会太早
Mina, why have you become so stubborn?
深那 你怎么变得这么固执
You've never been like this before.
你以前从来不会这样啊
I also don't want Ichinose's family to suffer as a result of this.
我也不想因为这种事情 破坏一之濑同学的家庭关系
Please, come back.
拜托你回来吧
Excuse me, could you hear her out a bit more?
不好意思 你们可以好好听听她的想法吗
Ichinose is really hardworking.
一之濑同学她真的很努力
She's very proactive about her job.
工作也很积极
"Proactive"?
积极？
That's what I think.
我个人觉得...
It's natural for you to begin dating and leave her alone,
学长学姐你们交往之后忽视了妹妹
and for her to decide
然后你妹妹因此决定学着独立
to be independent as a result.
这两件事都是理所当然的吧
You may have a point.
你说得是有点道理...
Mina is shy. She obviously forces herself to do this.
但深那是个内向的孩子 她一定是在勉强自己这么做
That's right, we genuinely care about Mina.
没错 我们是真心替她着想...
Seniors, do you know how old Ichinose is this year?
学长 学姐 你们以为一之濑同学今年几岁了呢
She sincerely wants to bless you.
她是真心想祝福你们
And chose this path because of that.
才做出了这个选择
Are you planning to take away this opportunity?
你们是打算夺走她成长的机会吗
We didn't…
我们没那个意思...
I don't have the authority to order you to leave her.
我并没资格叫学长你远离自己的妹妹
But isn't it incorrect to believe
但如果你觉得 妹妹留在自己身边是天经地义
that your sister will always be by your side?
这种想法本身不正确吧
Will everyone's smiles fade if the sister stops relying on her brother?
当你妹妹不再依赖你 难道大家就会失去笑容了吗
That's not true, is it?
不是这样的吧？
As her senior at work, I've been watching her develop. If you ask me,
身为在一旁看着她打工的前辈 若要我说的话...
Ichinose's future will be decided
能决定一之濑同学将来的
when she can express herself
只有等到她能用自己的话语
in her own words.
表达自己想法的时候 不是吗
For the time being, we've bought some time.
我们暂且争取到了一点时间
Hmm, thank you.
嗯 谢谢你
What's wrong?
怎么了
E-Excuse me, did I do something wrong?
请问...我是不是做错了什么
Because every time I make a mistake, you come to remind me.
因为我每次做错时 你都会来提醒我
We're not at work now.
现在又不是在打工
We know what's right and what's wrong, don't we?
是对是错 自己心里有数就好了吧
When I arrived here, I was thinking,
我们来这里的时候我就在想
"I don't understand other people's problems,"
别人的家务事我又不了解
so I decided to judge everything
所以我就决定以打工前辈的身份
as your senior at work.
来判断一切
Your brother showed up to pick you up.
你哥哥他们想来带你回去
This may seem right to others.
这在旁人眼中或许是正确的举动
But,
但是
in that case, what have you worked so hard for so far?
既然这样你这么努力打工至今 又是为了什么呢
Being scolded by rude customers, apologizing to them,
你被不讲理的客人为难 低头道歉
even though it's something you're not good at, you've overcome it one by one.
就算不擅长的事情 你也一件又一件地克服
I've seen it all.
我全都看在眼里
INTERN You really worked hard.
(实习中) 你真的很努力
Who's going to be able to handle it if it all comes to nothing?
如果要让这一切化为泡影 谁能接受得了啊
Ah, that…
啊...你...
CAMPUS OPEN DAY BRIEFING, THIS WAY
(校园参观日说明会 会场请往此)
Good morning.
早呀
Natsukawa, long time no see.
夏川 好久不见
Huh? You seem different somehow?
咦 你好像变得不太一样了
I got a bit tanned and built some muscles.
我晒黑了点 还练了点肌肉
Because I've been running outside all the time.
因为我一直在户外跑步
Right, after all, sports clubs are busy.
也对 毕竟体育社团很忙嘛
Did you go somewhere fun during the summer vacation?
你暑假有去哪玩吗
I'll go get it for you, you sit down.
我去帮你拿 你坐下吧
Sorry to keep you waiting.
久等了
T-Thank you.
嗯...谢谢你
What's wrong? Sasaki?
佐佐木同学你怎么了
No, nothing. It's okay.
啊不... 没什么
Is that so?
哦...
Good morning, Ichinose.
早啊 一之濑同学
INTERN H-How is it?
(实习中) 你觉得怎么样
Good job.
不错哦
Hello.
你好
I'm here again, Senior Ichinose.
一之濑学姐 我又来了
Mr. Sajo, hello.
佐城先生你好
Welcome.
欢迎光临
I've finished the book you recommended.
我看完了你之前推荐我的那本书
Huh? That's fast.
咦 这么快
Yes, the final Strawberry Tart Operation was really impressive.
是的 最后的草莓塔作战 真是令人印象深刻
I didn't expect the pastry chef to be such a bad person.
没想到糕点师傅竟然那么差劲
I know. The clever foreshadowing and the intriguing theme are both excellent.
我懂！不仅伏笔巧妙 题材也吸引人 真的很棒
You're at work now.
现在是工作时间哦
I'm sorry.
对不起
Chatting to Senior Ichinose was so much fun that I got carried away.
跟一之濑学姐聊天太开心了 害我不小心就...
I'm sorry.
对不起
Ichinose.
一之濑同学
Do you know what day it is today?
你知道今天是什么日子吗
T-Today?
今天吗...
It's the day your internship ends.
今天是你实习期间结束的日子
Congratulations.
恭喜你